[{"question": "\[
\begin{array}{|l|l|l|l|}
\hline
i. & \text{False whorl like inflorescence} & \text{Many sessile bisexual flowers} & \text{Leonotis} \\
\hline
ii. & \text{Single flower like inflorescence} & \text{Many stalked staminate and pistillate flowers} & \text{Poinsettia} \\
\hline
\text{iii.} & \text{Fruit-like inflorescence} & \text{Many sessile staminate flowers on the top and pistillate flowers at the base and sterile flowers in between} &  \\
\hline
\text{iv.} & \text{Fleshy axis of inflorescence} & \text{Many stalked staminate flowers at the base and pistillate flowers on the top and sterile flowers in between} &  \\
\hline
\end{array}
\]
", "options": ["Option A", "Option B", "Option C", "Option D"], "correctoption": "Correct Option"}, {"question": "If two vessels $A$ and $B$ contain the same gas but the volume of vessel $A$ is twice that of $B$ and temperature and pressure of gas $\\mathrm{A}$ is twice that of gas in $\\mathrm{B}$, then the ratio of gas molecules in A and B is", "options": ["$1: 2$", "$1: 4$", "$4: 1$", "$2: 1$  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "At constant volume, temperature is increased then", "options": ["collision on walls will be less", "number of collisions per unit time will increase", "collisions will be in straight lines", "collisions will not change.  "], "correctoption": "B"}, {"question": "If a gas is heated at constant pressure, its isothermal compressibility", "options": ["remains constant", "increases linearly with temperature", "decreases linearly with temperature", "decreases inversely with temperature  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "Agas in a container $A$ is in thermal equilibrium with antoher gas of the same mass in container $B$. If we denote the corresponding pressures and volumes by the suffixes $\\mathrm{A}$ and $\\mathrm{B}$, then which of the following statement is most likely to be true?", "options": ["$\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{A}}=\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{B}}, \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{A}} \\neq \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{B}}$", "$\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{A}} \\neq \\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{B}}, \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{A}}=\\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{B}}$", "$\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{A}} / \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{A}}=\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{B}} / \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{B}}$", "$\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{A}} \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{A}}=\\mathrm{P}_{\\mathrm{B}} \\mathrm{V}_{\\mathrm{B}}$  "], "correctoption": "C"}, {"question": "In a cubical vessel are enclosed $n$ molecules of a gas each having a mass $\\mathrm{m}$ and an average speed $\\mathrm{v}$. If $\\ell$ is the length of each edge of the cube, the pressure exerted by the gas will be", "options": ["$\\frac{n \\mathrm{mv}^{2}}{\\ell^{3}}$", "$\\frac{n m^{2} v}{2 \\ell^{3}}$", "$\\frac{\\mathrm{mnv^{2 }}}{3 \\ell^{3}}$", "$\\frac{\\mathrm{nmv}}{2 \\ell}$  "], "correctoption": "D"}, {"question": "$P, V, T$ respectively denote pressure, volume and temperature of two gases. On mixing, new temperature and volume are respectively $T$ and $V$. Final pressure of the mixture is", "options": ["$P$", "$2 P$", "zero", "$3 P$  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "Gas at a pressure $P_{0}$ is contained in a vessel. If the masses of all the molecules are halved and their speeds are doubled, the resulting pressure $P$ will be equal to", "options": ["$4 P_{0}$", "$2 P_{0}$", "$P_{0}$", "$\\frac{P_{0}}{2}$  "], "correctoption": "B"}, {"question": "The temperature at which the average transitional kinetic energy of a gas molecule is equal to the energy gained by an electron in accelerating from rest through a potential difference of 1 volt is", "options": ["$4.6 \\times 10^{3} \\mathrm{~K}$", "$11.6 \\times 10^{3} \\mathrm{~K}$", "$23.2 \\times 10^{3} \\mathrm{~K}$", "$7.7 \\times 10^{3} \\mathrm{~K}$  "], "correctoption": "C"}, {"question": "$4.0 \\mathrm{~g}$ of a gas occupies 22.4 litres at NTP. The specific heat capacity of the gas at constant volume is $5.0 \\mathrm{JK}^{-1}$. If the speed of sound in this gas at NTP is $952 \\mathrm{~ms}^{-1}$, then the heat capacity at constant pressure is (Take gas constant $\\mathrm{R}=8.3$ $\\mathrm{JK}^{-1} \\mathrm{~mol}^{-1}$ )", "options": ["$7.5 \\mathrm{JK}^{-1} \\mathrm{~mol}^{-1}$", "$7.0 \\mathrm{JK}^{-1} \\mathrm{~mol}^{-1}$", "$8.5 \\mathrm{JK}^{-1} \\mathrm{~mol}^{-1}$", "$8.0 \\mathrm{JK}^{-1} \\mathrm{~mol}^{-1}$  "], "correctoption": "D"}, {"question": "Two vessels separately contain two ideal gases $A$ and $B$ at the same temperature. The pressure of $A$ being twice that of B. Under such conditions, the density of $A$ is found to be 1.5 times the density of $B$. The ratio of molecular weight of $A$ and $B$ is :", "options": ["$\\frac{3}{4}$", "2", "$\\frac{1}{2}$", "$\\frac{2}{3}$  "], "correctoption": "D"}, {"question": "The ratio of the specific heats $\\frac{C_{p}}{C_{v}}=\\gamma$ in terms of degrees of freedom ( $\\mathrm{n}$ ) is given by", "options": ["$\\left(1+\\frac{\\mathrm{n}}{3}\\right)$", "$\\left(1+\\frac{2}{\\mathrm{n}}\\right)$", "$\\left(1+\\frac{n}{2}\\right)$", "$\\left(1+\\frac{1}{\\mathrm{n}}\\right)$"], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "For hydrogen gas $C_{p}-C_{v}=a$ and for oxygen gas $C_{p}-C_{v}=b$. So, the relation between $a$ and $b$ is given by", "options": ["$a=16 b$", "$16 \\mathrm{a}=\\mathrm{b}$", "$\\mathrm{a}=4 \\mathrm{~b}$", "$\\mathrm{a}=\\mathrm{b}$  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "The temperature at which protons in hydrogen gas would have enough energy to overcome Coulomb barrier of $4.14 \\times 10^{-14} \\mathrm{~J}$ is(Boltzmann constant $=1.38 \\times 10^{-23} \\mathrm{JK}^{-1}$ )", "options": ["$2 \\times 10^{9} \\mathrm{~K}$", "$10^{9} \\mathrm{~K}$", "$6 \\times 10^{9} \\mathrm{~K}$", "$3 \\times 10^{9} \\mathrm{~K}$  "], "correctoption": "C"}, {"question": "The temperature at which oxygen molecules have the same root mean square speed as that of hydrogen molecules at $300 \\mathrm{~K}$ is", "options": ["$600 \\mathrm{~K}$", "$2400 \\mathrm{~K}$", "$4800 \\mathrm{~K}$", "$300 \\mathrm{~K}$  "], "correctoption": "B"}, {"question": "If the root mean square velocity of the molecules of hydrogen at NTP is $1.84 \\mathrm{~km} / \\mathrm{s}$. Calculate the root mean square velocity of oxygen molecule at NTP, molecular weight of hydrogen and oxygen are 2 and 32 respectively", "options": ["$1.47 \\mathrm{~km} / \\mathrm{sec}$", "$0.94 \\mathrm{~km} / \\mathrm{s}$", "$1.84 \\mathrm{~km} / \\mathrm{s}$", "$0.47 \\mathrm{~km} / \\mathrm{sec}$"], "correctoption": "B"}, {"question": null, "options": [null, null, null, null], "correctoption": null}, {"question": "$\\quad \\lim _{x \\rightarrow 3}([x-3]+[3-x]-x)$, where [.] denotes the greatest integer function, is equal to", "options": ["4", "-4", "0", "does not exist\n\n  "], "correctoption": "C"}, {"question": "Let $f(x)= \\begin{cases}x+1, & x>0 \\\\ 2-x, & x \\leq 0\\end{cases}$\n\nand $g(x)=\\left\\{\\begin{array}{cc}x+3, & x<1 \\\\ x^{2}-2 x-2, & 1 \\leq x<2 \\\\ x-5, & x \\geq 2\\end{array}\\right.$ then $\\lim _{x \\rightarrow 0} g(f(x))$ is", "options": ["2", "1", "-3", "does not exist\n\n  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "$\\quad \\lim _{x \\rightarrow 0} \\frac{\\sin [\\cos x]}{1+[\\cos x]}$ ([.] denotes the greatest integer function)", "options": ["equal to 1", "equal to 0", "does not exist", "None of these\n\n  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "If $f: R \\rightarrow R$ is defined by $f(x)=[x-3]+|x-4|$ for $x \\in R$, then $\\lim _{x \\rightarrow 3^{-}} f(x)$ is equal to (where [.] represents the greatest integer function)", "options": ["-2", "-1", "0", "1\n\n  "], "correctoption": "D"}, {"question": "$\\quad \\lim _{x \\rightarrow-7} \\frac{[x]^{2}+15[x]+56}{\\sin (x+7) \\sin (x+8)}=$ (where [.] denotes the greatest integer function)", "options": ["is 0", "is 1", "is - 1", "does not exist\n\n  "], "correctoption": "A"}, {"question": "The value of $\\lim _{x \\rightarrow 0^{+}}(1+[x])^{1 / x}$, where $[x]$ is the greatest integer $\\leq x$, is", "options": ["e", "1", "does not exist", "0\n\n  "], "correctoption": "C"}, {"question": "$\\lim _{x \\rightarrow \\infty}\\left(\\frac{1}{e}-\\frac{x}{1+x}\\right)^{x}$ is equal to", "options": ["$\\frac{\\mathrm{e}}{1-\\mathrm{e}}$", "0", "$e^{\\frac{e}{1-e}}$", "does not exist\n\n  "], "correctoption": "D"}, {"question": "The figure shows an isosceles triangle $A B C$ with $\\angle B=\\angle C$. The bisector of angle $B$ intersects the side $A C$ at the point $P$. Suppose that $B C$ remains fixed but the altitude AM approaches 0 , so that $A \\rightarrow M$ (mid-point of $B C$ ). Limiting value of $B P$, is (where a is fixed side $B C$ )\n\n\n\\includegraphics[max width=\\textwidth, center]{img4}", "options": ["$\\frac{a}{3}$", "$\\frac{a}{2}$", "$\\frac{2 a}{3}$", "$\\frac{3 a}{4}$"], "correctoption": "B"}]
